there is a common perception that
Western medicine is science-based
right evidence-based is kind of the
primary term there are websites on
science-based medicines that are focused
on showing what kind of scientific
research is missing for things outside
of traditional Western approach and that
natural medicine is generally some
degree of folk superstitions with maybe
a little bit that has science and a
little bit that is like hocus pocus
stuff and I think that's actually fair
oftentimes when we come to I mean
there's obviously an assumption that if
something is natural it's good for you
that some people have that is very
unsophisticated and if something
synthetic gets bad for you that's
oversimplified and muscle testing is
very different diagnostic method than
actually running labs and but what I'm
wanting to bring about is that what I'm
wanting you to get into here is it a
naturally oriented medicine doesn't mean
not high-tech and it doesn't mean not
high science it means that it's science
trying to understand what the nature of
physiology is normally doing rather than
just saying how do we override one very
small part of it but to just speak to
that for a minute because when you say
there's a divine intelligence right that
can also kind of speak to the like oh so
are you doing prayer healing so a little
bit more does is Thea's Umrah quired is
any particular other than rational
belief system required and is what
you're doing drawing upon the sciences I
love this question and I wish we had all
night to talk about it because there's
so many different directions we could go
there so I'll just take the theism first
no absolutely not there's no religion in
here it is for me maybe you could
classify it as a religion but there is a
certainty within me and it is my truth
with a capital T that every human body
is capable of healing so I start every
interaction with any person whether
they're a patient or not under the
assumption that they can heal
and whatever stands in their way can be
moved does that answer the the god
question so when you say a divine
intelligence mm-hmm what you mean by
that
and I would say maybe in a if I'm gonna
translate it into a closer to science
language is that this is a
self-organizing system that has very
complex regulatory mechanisms that
evolved to regulate well yeah and if
they're not regulating well there's
probably some problem in the way that if
you identify it and clear it it's it
actually evolved to regulate well
precisely you know and I don't know the
details of human evolution that's not my
area of expertise but exactly we came
out of a system that the earth right we
were here in earth and things like sea
salt like we're understanding more and
more and more how sea salt is I created
in these perfect ratios of these
micronutrients that we need and you know
we were created on earth where the sea
salt exists and instead of taking a
bunch of calcium and magnesium maybe it
makes more sense to get some sea salts
and that our blood pressure will be
better regulated that our adrenals will
we be redder better regulated excuse me
that all of these things might run a
little better if they are supported in a
natural system now going that in a
natural way
that's an alignment with the way we
evolved to watch the full episode or to
subscribe to the podcast click the link
in the description or visit
at neuro hacker.com slash collective
insights
[Music]